<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Viz | Brendan Graham</title>
    <link>https://brendangraham.netlify.com/tags/data-viz/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://brendangraham.netlify.com/tags/data-viz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Data Viz</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Brendan Graham, 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://brendangraham.netlify.com/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Data Viz</title>
      <link>https://brendangraham.netlify.com/tags/data-viz/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone Everywhere Music Analysis Tool</title>
      <link>https://brendangraham.netlify.com/project/spotify_analyzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://brendangraham.netlify.com/project/spotify_analyzer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This app calls the Spotify API and leverages the &amp;ldquo;Features&amp;rdquo; that Spotify uses to classify songs. This project started when we were joking that we could use AI to write a new Everyone Everywhere song. That conversation reminded me of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://peerchristensen.netlify.com/post/clustering-springsteen-albums-with-spotifyr/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; I had seen where the author used the &lt;code&gt;spotifyR&lt;/code&gt; package to get song data and analyze the songs. I thought it would be interesting to analyze my own band&amp;rsquo;s songs in the same manner, and also provide anyone a way to search for bands and see how Spotify classifies their songs in terms of energy, danceability, valence, liveness, etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;check-out-the-app-herehttpsbrndngrhmshinyappsioeveryoneeverywheremusicanalysistool&#34;&gt;Check out the app &lt;a href=&#34;https://brndngrhm.shinyapps.io/EveryoneEverywhereMusicAnalysisTool/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon load, the app displays an analysis of Everyone Everywhere tracks. A user can pick a feature, such as energy, and the app will rank tracks according to energy, and show a distribution of track energy for every album associated with the band. The lower left chart uses k-means to cluster artist tracks, and the lower right radar charts show how albums compare to each other across several features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about the development process on my &lt;a href=&#34;wwww.example.com&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; or view the project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RideTracker</title>
      <link>https://brendangraham.netlify.com/project/ride_tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://brendangraham.netlify.com/project/ride_tracker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://brndngrhm.shinyapps.io/RideTracker/&#34;&gt;RideTracker&lt;/a&gt; app was the first reactive data viz app I developed. It provides a way for me to track my training and commuting, in both a weekly snapshot view as well as over time, in ways that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fawda123/rStrava&#34;&gt;Strava&lt;/a&gt; user profile page doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, I&amp;rsquo;d been seeing so many cool examples of Shiny apps and really wanted to make my own. I decided to make one using my Cycling data because I had just started to take training seriously and began racing competitively. I was looking for a way to analyze my training volume on a weekly basis and comparatively over time. The App is built on the &lt;code&gt;flexdashboard&lt;/code&gt; framework with a &lt;code&gt;Shiny&lt;/code&gt; reactive engine allowing me to dynamically filter the charts based on the sidebar inputs. I was able to retrieve my data using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fawda123/rStrava&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;rStrava&lt;/code&gt; package&lt;/a&gt;, and created all the charts using the  &lt;code&gt;highcharter&lt;/code&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about the development process on my &lt;a href=&#34;wwww.example.com&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; or view the project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brndngrhm/rides&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
